<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Work on Slawomir Slav Jasinski</title><link>/categories/work/</link><description>Recent content in Work on Slawomir Slav Jasinski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:30:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS Cost Optimization - A Solution Architect's Guide</title><link>/2024/aws-cost-optimization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 09:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2024/aws-cost-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;p>As cloud adoption continues to surge, managing AWS costs has become a critical skill for IT professionals. Here are key strategies I&amp;rsquo;ve found effective:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5 Key Strategies to Effective Team Expectation Management</title><link>/2024/effective-team-expectation-management/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 09:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2024/effective-team-expectation-management/</guid><description>Over the years, I have learned that managing team expectations is crucial for the success of a project. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re deploying complex cloud solutions or leading any tech initiative, clear communication and alignment are key.
Here are 5 strategies I&amp;rsquo;ve found effective in setting and managing expectations:
5 Key Strategies to Effective Team Expectation Management 1. Collaborate on Goals Involve your team in setting expectations to boost buy-in and motivation.</description></item><item><title>AWS Hidden Gems Mastering Athena, Config, and More</title><link>/2024/aws-advanced-services-for-solutions-architects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 09:30:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2024/aws-advanced-services-for-solutions-architects/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ve mastered EC2, S3 and VPC fundamentals. But to truly shine as an AWS Solutions Architect, you need to go beyond the basics. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore five &amp;ldquo;hidden gems&amp;rdquo; that will elevate your architecture game:
1. Athena Problem: Analyzing massive datasets stored in S3 can be a nightmare. Solution: Serverless query service for analyzing data directly in S3 using standard SQL. Impact: Enables real-time insights from your data without managing infrastructure. 2.</description></item><item><title>Unlocking Tribal Knowledge in the Business Campfire</title><link>/2024/unlocking-tribal-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2024/unlocking-tribal-knowledge/</guid><description>Transforming Knowledge into Power: Why Sharing is Crucial in Business 🌟 In every organization, there is that one person who seems to have all the answers. Colleagues flock to them with issues, relying on their expertise to resolve challenges. While having such knowledgeable individuals can seem like a boon, it begs the question: is this reliance a strength or a potential risk for the company?
The Double-Edged Sword of Expertise Experts within a company are invaluable, but dependence on them can inadvertently create bottlenecks and knowledge silos.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing Security During Client Visits - Best Practices</title><link>/2024/security/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2024/security/</guid><description>Working with multiple clients across various settings has taught me the importance of robust security practices—and provided a few humorous yet educational moments when these rules were overlooked!
Here’s how you can keep your reputation and data safe and avoid common pitfalls when working offsite:
🔒 Always Log Out: Ensure to log out from all devices when stepping away, even for brief moments. This simple action can protect sensitive information from unauthorized access or awful jokes from security guys 😂</description></item><item><title>Shifting to a cloud-native architecture</title><link>/2024/cloud-native-architecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2024/cloud-native-architecture/</guid><description>Shifting to a cloud-native architecture 🌐 is not just a trend—it&amp;rsquo;s a strategic move that can propel your applications to new heights in terms of flexibility, scalability, and performance. Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving deep into the when, why, and how of making this crucial transition, with an eye on navigating the choices between cloud-native and traditional setups 🚀.
Let&amp;rsquo;s also tackle a common concern: the risk of vendor lock-in, and explore &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; strategies to mitigate this issue.</description></item><item><title>Consultants Are Like Avocados</title><link>/2024/consultants-are-like-avocados/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2024/consultants-are-like-avocados/</guid><description>Do you think consultants are useless? Think again! 🙌 My latest article is a Friday-perfect, lighthearted counterpoint to Steve Jobs&amp;rsquo; grumbles about consultants. Get ready to change your mind!
Steve Jobs on Consultants? Hold My Latte All right, let&amp;rsquo;s be honest. We all love Steve Jobs - the vision, the turtleneck, the whole deal. But when it came to consultants, the guy could be…well, a little harsh. He famously tossed shade, saying stuff like consultants don&amp;rsquo;t own solutions, and their expertise is all theoretical book-smarts.</description></item><item><title>Talking about AI and ML at Onet</title><link>/onet-talk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/onet-talk/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m is explaining how Ringier Axel Springer Polska and Onet are innovating with #AI and #MachineLearning - e.g. to ensure the diversity in the media.</description></item><item><title>AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate</title><link>/aws-certified-solutions-architect/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/aws-certified-solutions-architect/</guid><description>After a decade of working with AWS, I am thrilled to share that I have earned my first professional certificate as a Solution Architect. I am both surprised and humbled by this achievement.
23T0L60C6NE41F3G ( https://aws.amazon.com/verification )</description></item><item><title>Another day another award…</title><link>/another-day-another-award/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 02:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/another-day-another-award/</guid><description>&lt;p>For 3 years in a row I’ve been working on Telstra NYE Mobile APP (via Imagination) and this time we won Awards. Obviously credits goes to whole team – but I’m glad the we make it this time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GE Ecomagination Centre</title><link>/ge-ecomagination-centre/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ge-ecomagination-centre/</guid><description>GE Ecomagination Centre is the 840 square-metre space in Masdar City’s Incubator Building, showcases GE’s advanced technologies from cleaner solutions for power grids to upmarket appliances.
I was heavily involved with building and designing some cool elements of this centre.</description></item><item><title>Talk: from light bulb to Arduino</title><link>/talk-from-light-bulb-to-arduino/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 06:08:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talk-from-light-bulb-to-arduino/</guid><description>I had opportunity to give a talk small talk about my work with Arduino on Commerce Factory – Nov 2014.
Slides are available here:
www.slideshare.net You can check video here</description></item><item><title>Interface Colour Play website</title><link>/interface-colour-play-website/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2014 06:48:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/interface-colour-play-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>Very nice website for Interface – utility for clients to match tiles based on inspirational images. Build while working in Imagination for Interface.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Facebook APP – photo competition for AMEX</title><link>/facebook-app-photo-competition-for-amex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 06:43:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>/facebook-app-photo-competition-for-amex/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amex Picture This – Facebook application build for American Express while working for Imagination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users could enter their propositions for AMEX Picture This competition – second phase – voting system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p> &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web Acronyms</title><link>/web-acronyms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 07:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>/web-acronyms/</guid><description>Short presentation which I gave couple years ago while working at Imagination
Slide available here:
Web Acronyms</description></item><item><title>Microsite for contact centre technology platform</title><link>/microsite-for-contact-centre-technology-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 04:42:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/microsite-for-contact-centre-technology-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p>Website build for one of the biggest technology platform for contact centre.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Centenary Quest – Facebook APP</title><link>/centenary-quest-facebook-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 06:39:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/centenary-quest-facebook-app/</guid><description>&lt;p>Facebook APP (competition) build in Imagination for CBA.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>